# STEPHANIE T. McCallum, MBA

4993 Southgate Parkway ● Myrtle Beach, SC 29579 ● (843) 424-0557 ● smccallum@coastal.edu

**HARD-WORKING AND DEDICATED** business educational professional that is creative, resourceful with four years of varied instructional experience. Possesses an effective, positive, and flexible teaching style with the willingness to work beyond the call of duty.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Student -Development
- Internal Controls/ Policy & Procedures
- Business Education

- Organization and Planning
- Classroom Management

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## COASTAL CAROLINA UNIVERSITY - Conway, SC

Accounts Payable Accountant, July 2016 to present

- Assisting with day-to-day book keeping with the University and related foundations Processing of timely payments to vendors for invoices supported with appropriate PO receipt and Management approval as required, ensuring compliance to company policies.
- Performing daily routine checks on problem situations and contacting vendors or departments if needed for problem resolution Review all incoming invoices for both non-purchase orders and purchase orders
- Coordinating travel and Accounts Payable paperwork; collecting, securing approvals, and reviewing payment expenditure and travel policy for reimbursement requests for account accuracy and authorization.
- Review vouchers to verify that an appropriate account, department is used each time. Ensure all submitted
  payment requests have proper back-up documentation, accurate coding, required signatures for approval, and
  ensure compliance with corporate policy.
- Review Duplicate report (internal control) preventing duplication of payment to vendors weekly
- Preform Petty Cash/Change Funds audits quarterly.

### HORRY GEORGETOWN TECHNICAL COLLEGE - Conway, SC

Adjunct Instructor, January 2015 to present (Business Education/College Freshmen Seminar)

- Part-time instructor responsible for instructing online and face to face academic subject area of Business/Freshmen Seminar in classrooms of up to 25 students.
- Tailor course material and present it in a manner that provides each student the opportunity to earn a passing grade in the course by integrating real world experiences into teaching curriculum.
- Evaluate student performance based on course objectives and course rubrics. All course grades & attendance are posted in D2L.

## MILLER- MOTTE TECHNICAL COLLEGE - Conway, SC

<u>Adjunct Instructor/Hybrid Teacher Assistant</u> March 2014 to November 2016 (General Education)

(Career Development, Computer Applications)

- Maintains a thorough knowledge and understanding of all school policies, and adheres to and upholds implementation and enforcement.
- Provides students with a full understanding of course objectives (syllabus, course outlines, and course materials/equipment) on the first day of class and throughout the course (6 week; 12 week).
- Facilitates classroom instruction in accordance with learning objectives and session plan outlines specified by the school.

## Online Adjunct Instructor, January 2012 to March 2014 (Accounting Principles)

- Work in an online learning environment and provide guidance to nontraditional undergraduates in 6 or 12 week
- Delivers feedback on student accounting projects through Moodle, (tutor struggling students).
- Respond promptly to students for grade determination by submitting grades for assignments, discussion board exercises, and exams.

## STEPHANIE T. McCallum, MBA

BOULINEAUS, INC. - Cherry Grove Beach (NMB), SC

Accounting Associate, March 2010 – July 2014

- Assumed responsibility for the full cycle Accounts Payable process (coding, data entry, check processing)
- Handled data entry and general ledger work as well as bookkeeping and general clerical tasks; record daily deposits
  in Great Plains, Journal entries monthly.
- Reconcile bank statements (Operating, Payroll) on a monthly basis for different Boulineaus owned companies.
- Trial Balance review on a monthly basis.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

## HORRY COUNTY SCHOOLS (K-12) – Myrtle Beach, SC

Substitute Teacher, October 2008 – November 2011

- Maintain classroom management to ensure an effective learning environment.
- Follow instructional lesson plans left by regular teacher.
- Assume all duties of the regular classroom teacher promptly and in accordance with school rules.

## BURROUGHS & CHAPIN COMPANY, INC - Myrtle Beach, SC

Accounting Associate, November 2002 – October 2008

- Oversaw the payment of invoices, proofing of checks and communication with outside vendors.
- Coordinate the collection of credit card reports, audit expense reports and identify improper charges.
- Reconcile bank statements for operations on a monthly basis.
- P&L and Balance Sheet review monthly.

### **EDUCATION**

FRANCIS MARION UNIVERSITY – Florence, SC **Bachelor of Business Administration in Accounting,** 2000

WEBSTER UNIVERSITY- Myrtle Beach, SC **Masters of Business Administration,** 2009

### **TECHNOLOGY SUMMARY**

MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook) ● Great Plains ● Windows ●D2L●MOODLE – QuickBooks Datatel (Colleague)

(843) 424-0557 ● smccallum@coastal.edu